SAMEEHA RAHMAN

London, United Kingdom +447704467608 rahman.sameeha@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sameeha-rahman samsam-026.github.io github.com/samsam-026

FRONT END DEVELOPER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

A degree-educated developer with three academic qualifications in the field and working knowledge in web technologies. An engineer who stays up to date on recent technologies, who constantly revises software best practices and user experience guidelines.

EDUCATION

M. Sc. Computer Science | Queen Mary University of London (Sept. 2020 – Oct. 2022)

Awarded **MSc with Distinction** for a 2-year part-time Computer Science postgraduate degree, studying Functional Programming, Interactive System Design, Mobile Services and Design for Human Interaction.

B. Eng. Software Engineering | University of Westminster (Sept. 2016 – July 2020)

Awarded **First Class Honours** for a 4-year Software Engineering undergraduate degree offered by the University of Westminster, UK, in partnership with the Informatics Institute of Technology, Sri Lanka.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer | Housekeep Ltd. (Nov. 2022 – Present)

Developed features and improved internal architecture of the Housekeeper and Customer mobile applications. Improved SEO score and page speed on marketing website by 50%. Increased unit testing coverage by 50% on owned app project.

Technology: Angular, Ionic, Next.js, React, Jasmine, PostgreSQL, AWS, Sentry.

Senior Developer | Switchd Ltd. (Sept. 2020 – Nov. 2022)

Defined and developed the company's coding and testing protocols. Implemented company finance processes using Xero APIs, saving 75% finance admin time. Reduce admin time on green home product installations by 50% for MakeMyHouseGreen.

Technology: HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL, AWS, Sentry.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Java, React.js, React Native, Flutter, Ionic, Angular, Typescript, Jasmine, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Jest, Figma, Git, AWS.

ACTIVITIES

Projects

Developer | first-born (2019)

A React Native UI framework consisting of inbuilt components developed using Atomic design, with over 2000 downloads and 200 stars on GitHub. This highly customizable library allows UI components to render separately according to the underlying platform, following platform UX guidelines, reducing the work of front-end developers.

Technology: React Native, Jest, ESLint.